# ANDREW LAZENKA

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

M

andrewlazenka@gmail.com

(3)

(416) 986-9241

andrewlazenka.com

 $\Box$ 

github.com/ALazenka

9

Markham, ON

## **EDUCATION**

# BACHELOR OF COMPUTING Queen's University

Sept 2015 - April 2020

Specialization in Software Design with Professional Internship

#### **SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

Ruby

PHP

Python

Java

C/C++

Go Elixir

**TECHNOLOGIES** 

React

Node

GraphQL

Rails

ElasticSearch

Redis

Docker

Git

AWS

Sentry

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

A solutions-driven, self-starting developer with a uniquely empathetic outlook on customer service. My expert leadership abilities have proven to spearhead the development lifecycle of projects from prototype through to production, encouraging growth and communication along the way. Being a naturally curious person, I enjoy learning and working within the full tech stack, and continually look to adopt new tools and organizational processes.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD**

Innovasium | April 2020 - Present

- Architected a robust, multi-layer, fault-tolerant data ingestion workflow using AWS (Lambda, S3, SNS, ElasticSearch), scaling to handle throughput of 1000 files concurrently
- Engineered a customizable UI rendering engine for composing data rich views using React, Highcharts and websockets
- Foster a positive work environment by introducing weekly 1:1 meetings and code review with the development team to identify opportunities for career growth
- Increase task visibility, enhance process pipelines, and improve company & project documentation in an effort to transition the team into a permanent full-time remote environment
- Follow Agile methodologies and lead sprint planning in order to effectively and successfully iterate and ship fast

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN**

Innovasium | May 2018 - April 2020

- Championed architecture, development and deployment of multiple web applications using React & Redux, GraphQL, and NodeJS on top of AWS serverless technologies
- Migrated a legacy CMS onto AWS (ECS, S3, and RDS) increasing service uptime to 99.8%
- Engineered the company's first fully automatic CI/CD pipelines, reducing developer overhead by 10%
- Developed an efficient and effective onboarding process for development interns

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN**

Innovasium | May 2017 - September 2017

- Provisioned an auto-scaling PaaS application within an on-premise, enterprise network using Docker
- Developed a client-facing, no-code, drag 'n drop portal builder using React & Redux
- Architected a headless CMS API using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL
- Wrote RSpec unit and integration tests providing 97% code coverage
- Improved internal developer tooling using Webpack configurations to optimize LESS, ES5(+) and asset compilation